

Tiago Carreira DevOps Engineer

- Rio de Janeiro, Brazil
- © +55 21 98303-3680
- tiago.g.carreira.br@gmail.com
- inkedin.com/in/tcarreira
- github.com/tcarreira

Soft Skills

- Productivity passionate
- Fast learner
- Highly adaptable
- Proactive and autonomous
- Good communicator
- Friendly and team player

Technical Skills































Technological Values









Everything as code

Community

Personal Interests







Podcasts. Audiobooks

Activeness,

Learning,

Achievement Improving

Languages

Portuguese



English



Spanish



French

Having 10+ years of experience with DevOps, I'm experienced with modern technologies (eg: Docker), proficient with Linux systems and many DevOps tools (Kubernetes, CI/CD, IaC) and I'm a Python and Go developer.

Passionate about Linux, Open Source and productivity (I love scripting and automation). No person should be a single point of failure - procedures should be documented and/or automated.

I'm looking towards working with **smart people**, with whom I could learn and help learning; where **autonomy** is a valuable asset and improving is more important than finding who made a mistake.

WORK EXPERIENCE

DevOps / Cloud Specialist @ Globo.com

DevOps / Cloud Specialist - August 2020 - Present (2+ years) Prio de Janeiro, Brazil

- Maintaining an Open Source PaaS (Platform as a Service) in Go tsuru.io | github.com/tsuru
- Managing multiple Kubernetes Clusters (with custom resources) 300+ nodes | 15k+ pods
- Designed / improved CI/CD Pipelines, using Gitlab-CI and Docker
- Infrastructure deployment and automation at GCP with terraform

DevOps/Operations Engineer @ SAPO (BOLD by devoteam)

July 2017 - December 2019 (2 years 6 months) PLisbon, Portugal

- Implemented a monitoring stack with High Availability, using Grafana + Prometheus + Thanos
- Developed a Python/Django RESTful API for SSL Cert management (from scratch to production)
- DevOps advocate: improving Continuous Integration and best practices among the organization
- Data Center migration: bare metal, VM's, networking, data and storage (ensuring no downtime)
- Maintaining 500+ servers (using Puppet), 100+ services, both legacy and modern systems, on-call 24/7

DevOps Engineer @ Premium Minds

December 2013 - June 2017 (3 years 7 months) PLisbon, Portugal

- Migrated on-premises infrastructure to AWS (EC2, RDS, VPC, ...)
- Infrastructure as code with python/boto3
- Defined the infrastructure and deployment pipeline for a High Available service on AWS telpark.com
- Managing Continuous Integration using Jenkins and Puppet

EDUCATION

Certifications

- August 2022 CKA: Certified Kubernetes Administrator @ The Linux Foundation
- September 2021 GCP: Associate Cloud Engineer @ Google Cloud Certified

Training & Courses

- June 2022 CKA: Certified Kubernetes Administrator @ A Cloud Guru
- July 2021 Cloud Engineer @ Pluralsight
- May 2020 NDG Linux I/II course @ Cisco Networking Academy
- Jan 2019 LPI DevOps Tools Engineer @ Linux Academy

MSc. in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Técnico Lisboa - University of Lisbon | 2007 - 2013 [₱] Lisbon, Portugal

- Major / Minor: Robotics & Control Systems / Computers
- Principal subjects: Database management, Objects Oriented Programming, Robotics
- Thesis: Quadcopter/Drone Automatic Take Off / Landing on a (mobile) Docking Station

OTHER TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE & PROJECTS

2022 - Speaker @ Python Brasil (tsuru) - youtu.be/gyLS37NVQHw

FOSDEM 2022: Ubuntu stand website design & support - stands.fosdem.org/stands/ubuntu

 $\textbf{2021} - \textbf{TreeTree2}: computer architecture \ \textbf{I} - \underline{github.com/tcarreira/nand2tetris-autograder}$ 2020 - Podcasting (host, audio editor, web developer, designer) - github.com/marmita-de-redon Dashboard website project using Golang - github.com/tcarreira/roaw2020

2019 - Speaker @ Pyjamas Conf 2019 (Django on Docker) - aithub.com/tcarreira/django-docker Speaker @ Ubucon Europe 2019 (Docker) - tcarreira.github.io/presentations Volunteer (technical) @ Ubucon Europe 2019 - github.com/ubuconeurope

2018 - TreeTree2: HAC - Hacking the learn process on math/physics/programming with 10-16yo people

PERSONAL ENDEAVORS

Sports: running (marathon), cycling (Lisbon-Santiago 600+ Km), obstacle course racing, rock climbing Music: clarinet, transverse flute, guitar, piano

Music groups: company's band, TUIST.tecnico.ulisboa.pt, multiple choirs, philharmonic orchestra Video production: youtube.carreira.pw, youtu.be/IKvtB-vNOek

Podcasting: marmita.pt (github.com/Marmita-de-Redon)

Personal skills: therapeutic massage (advanced integrated therapeutic massage course) Maker: Arduino, Raspberry Pi